Hansraj Das

Software Developer at Google via GlobalLogic Inc.

G-318, Mangolpuri, 110083, New Delhi, Delhi India

hansrajdas



Seasoned software engineer with extensive experience in software/web development, testing and maintenance of complex products. Most of the work experience revolve around Python, C/C++ and Golang. Good understanding of databases - MySQL, SQLite and LDAP. In depth understanding of algorithms, data structures, time/space complexity and OOPs concepts. Posses good knowledge of designing/architecting, testing and deployment of softwares on various platforms. Also have hands on experience in front end frameworks/libraries - AngularJS, jQuery and python modules like numpy and pandas. Currently working as a developer for Google as TVC @Google Gurgaon, India.

SKILLS

Languages Master	Languages Intermediate	Framework Intermediate
python c/c++ shell scripting	golang javascript css html	angularjs jquery numpy pandas sqlalchemy webapp2
Databases Master	Software Tools Master	Server Master
mysql ldap	vim wireshark gdb valgrind callgrind purify bullseye jenkins	apache socket programming
Version Control Master	Operating System Master	Cloud Platform Tools Intermediate
git cvs svn	ubuntu unix linux windows	google appengine(gae) google cloud sql borg/kubernetes

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer at GlobalLogic **March 2017- Current** https://globallogic.com

Working on 2 google internal tools

- Improved tools performance, latency from 20 secs to 5 secs
- Implemented bulk edit functionality to update agent profiles in batches Based in Golang, Jquery, and CloudSQL
- Developed python and agularJS based tool to manage agent assignments
- Also working on various pipelines, dashboards, deployment platforms like google app engine, borg/kubernetes

Technical Leader at Aricent, Gurgaon October 2011- March 2017

https://www.aricent.com/

Majorly involved in development of HSS REST interface and LTE EPC

- Developed XML based REST interface to configure LTE HSS using python, C/C++, gSoap and apache web server
- Developed support for distributed HSS in EMS, EMS is a web based tool to configure LTE EPC nodes. Technologies used is python, C/C++, javascript and HTML
- Developed a python based tool to migrate routing configurations stored at Idap server (in Idif files) on new hardware platform
- Developed S6a and STa interface in HSS, in depth knowledge of diameter protocol
- Integrated all LTE EPC core network nodes (MME, SGW, PGW, HSS and PCRF)

EDUCATION

B.Tech Electronics and Communication at Bharati Vidyapeeth's College of Engineering **2007 - 2011**

Grade: 73.4%

XII Science at Kendriya Vidyalaya, Rohini, Delhi

2006 - 2007

Grade: 86.4%

AWARDS

Individual Excellence Award at Globallogic

Got individual excellence award for quarter Jan-Mar 2018

Aricent Training Project at Aricent

Won second prize for training project (network firewall) at aricent, Jan 2012

LANGUAGES

Hindi English
Native speaker (mother tongue) Native speaker